ROSHAN MAKHE

Address: C/o Dumbhare

Chintamani nagar, rmakhe@gmail.com
Besa Road, Manewada Cell no:+91-9096171557

Nagpur, Maharashtra-440024

India Blog: https://r7111roshan.blogspot.com

Summary:

With 1.9 years of experience in design and development of Java / J2EE web Applications.

Worked on variety of technologies like Java, Oracle PL/SQL, MySql,

JavaScript/Jquery, Ajax, HTML,CSS.

Worked on frameworks Struts 2.0, Hibernate and Bootstrap presentation framework.

Worked on Maven Based projects.

Experience of Implemented log4j into projects with created daily date wise log files.

Currently doing some project in spring framework.

OBJECTIVE:

To secure a position in an organization where I can learn and utilize my skills and experience to achieve organizational and personal goals.

Educational Qualification:

- Full Time Bachelors of Engineering in the specialization of Information Technology from Yeshwantrao Chavan College of Engineering, Wanadongri, Nagpur, Maharashtra with 62.08% in 8th semester which is recently autonomous engineering college.
- H.S.C passed from Gram vikas Arts & Science College Kondhi(Jawahar Nagar), Bhandara.
- 11th passed from Gram vikas Arts & Science College Kondhi(Jawahar Nagar), Bhandara with 70.83%.
- > S.S.C. passed from Ordnance Factory Jawahar Nagar School, Bhandara.

Technical Skills:

Core Java, OOP, Multithreading, Collection Framework, Data Structures, knowledge about Spring Framework, Spring MVC.

J2EE Technologies: JSP, Servlet, JDBC.

Java Frameworks: Struts 2 and Hibernate.

<u>Database</u>: Oracle 9i, 10g PL/SQL, MySQL(sqlyog).

Web Technologies: HTML, HTML 5, CSS, CSS3, AJAX, JavaScript/ Jquery.

Front-end framework: Bootstrap.

<u>Logging utility</u>: Log4j 1.2

Server: Apache Tomcat, GlassFish.

Build Tool: Maven

IDE: NetBeans 6.8, 7.4, 8.0 and Eclipse.

Experience:

From Jan 2016 to Present:

Currently doing some project in spring framework, Participated in codejam and kickstart, writing blogs, also I was preparing for the same competitive programming, social activity.

Technical Member (Java developer) in Lighthouse Info Systems Pvt. Ltd. (From 1st April 2014 To Jan 2016)

Work Responsibilities: Design and coding, Debugging applications, Documentation, Development of Web Applications using Web technologies, Java and J2EE technologies. Worked in a team to create projects.

Worked on Projects:

1. LHS Education ERP

Worked on student module, library module : used Struts 2.0 framework, AJAX etc.

Description:

Web based ERP solution for education Systems, provides a complete solution from promotion for admission to result.

Management including different login for different purposes like management, administration, parents, students, teachers etc.

Provides pre admission management(admission enquiries, follow ups), Hostel Management, Training and Placements, Transport management and almost every kind of activity in a medium and small sized education system.

- 2. CRM Portal: Used JSP, JavaScript, Java, Ajax, HTML.
- **3. taxcpc**: used Hibernate framework, Criteria Queries, Bootstrap framework.
- **4. LHSCARE**: used Hibernate framework, HQL queries, Bootstrap framework.
- **5. erpapprovals**: used Bootstrap framework, Apache logging utility(Log4j).
- **6. onlinegam**: used Bootstrap framework, Apache logging utility(Log4j).

Previous Experience:

Research Associate in EDR continuous Information Pvt.

Ltd.(bpsllc.net) (From 8th March 2011 To 9th July 2013)

• **Assistant (SEO)** in Vision Tek Software, Trimurti Nagar.

(From April 2010 To September 2010)

Certifications:

- Certificate of Core Java and Advance Java from Seed InfoTech.
- Web-I-Imagination in COMPUFEST 2008 (National level technical fest), organized by Department of Computer & Information Technology, YCCE
- Web Imagination in COMPUFEST 2009 (National level Technical Symposium), organized by Department of Computer & Information Technology, YCCE.
- > Online Java, JavaScript, SQL, C++ courses Completed.

Personal Information:

Name: Roshan Pramod Makhe Father's Name: Pramod Digambar Makhe

Gender: Male Marital Status: Single

Languages Known: English, Hindi, and Marathi.

Strengths: Dedication, Honest, Self Motivation.

Hobbies: Yoga, Reading, gardening.

Declaration: I hereby declare that all the above information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Thanking you

Date: 9th April, 2019 Yours faithfully

Place: Nagpur, Maharashtra, India

Roshan P. Makhe